Guide to the Epsilon Sigma Phi records, 1927-2001.
Epsilon Sigma Phi records, 1927-2001.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Epsilon Sigma Phi records, 1927-2001.
21-24-1979.
Epsilon Sigma Phi. Lambda Chapter.
4.4 cubic ft.
Records, correspondence, lists, speeches, minutes, financial reports, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Records of the Lambda Chapter of Epsilon Sigma Phi. Also, six volumes of the "Book of Annals," biographical sketches and photographs of Cornell extension and county extension staff.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Epsilon Sigma Phi is the National Honorary Extension Fraternity.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes constitution and bylaws, initiation material, a history of the fraternity, correspondence, awards, a speech, membership lists, minutes, financial reports, and other records of the Lambda Chapter of Epsilon Sigma Phi, including information concerning Cooperative Extension, New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Donald J. White, Russell C. Hodnett, and others. Also, six volumes of the "Book of Annals," biographical sketches and photographs of Cornell extension and county extension staff.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Epsilon Sigma Phi.; Hodnett, Russell C.; White, Donald J.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.
Subjects:
Agricultural extension work.
Form and Genre Terms:
Biographies.; Photographs.; Speeches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Epsilon Sigma Phi, Lambda Chapter. Records, 1927-2003
  - New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences. Lambda Chapter, Active Members., 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles of Incorporation and By Laws, Epsilon Sigma Phi. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Epsilon Sigma Phi History" by Luke M. Schruben, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Russell C. Hodnett, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Russell C. Hodnett, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Information and Letters, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Donald J. White Papers and Other Material, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Donald J. White Papers and Other Material, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annual Meetings, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1973 Initiates, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Awards of Merit, 1947-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Talk by E. S. Philips, Annual Meeting, February 27, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - National Council Meeting (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1975 Annual Meeting in Texas, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board and Committee Members, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Nominating Committee, 1968- (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1972, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1973 (Part 1), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1973 (Part 2), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1974 (Part 1), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1974 (Part 2), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1974 (Part 3), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1975, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1976, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1977, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1978, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi - 1979, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "The Lambda Briefs", 1962-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - National Council, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Retirement Committee, Files of C. A. Bratton, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Retirement Committee, Files of C. A. Bratton, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the Lambda Chapter (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - North Eastern Region, New York, National Meeting (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Constitution and By Laws (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Membership Files, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Membership Files, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Membership Files, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Executive Committee and Membership Committee Chairmen Files, 1958, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Financial Reports, Correspondence, Committee Meetings, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Board and Executive Committee Minutes, 1960, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Meetings, Budgets, Membership Lists, Correspondence, 1959-1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Board Meeting Minutes, Nominations for the Distinguished Service Ruby Certificate Award, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Membership Lists, Correspondence, General Records, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Active Membership Lists, Member Dues and Fees Paid, 1945-1955 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Budget Reports, Correspondence, Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Officers' List, Initiation Ceremony Ritual, Constitution and By Laws, Minutes of Meetings, Other Reports, 1935, 1943-1951 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Historical" List of Officers, Members: Associate, Honorary, Reserve and Deceased, 1927-1956 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Financial Records Including Checking and Savings Accounts, 1940-1954 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Annual Meetings, Awards Breakfasts, 1981-1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - General Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - General Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - State Certificates of Recognition Awarded by National Council (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - National Council Meetings and Directories, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - National Newsletters, 1976-1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Book of Annals (I) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Book of Annals (II) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Book of Annals (III) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Book of Annals (IV) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Book of Annals (V) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Book of Annals (VI) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Book of Annals (VII) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "The Lambda Briefs", 1985-1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "The Lambda Briefs", 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meetings, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meetings, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Annual Meetings, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Annual Meetings, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Annual Meetings, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report Material, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Annual Meetings, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Annual Meetings, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Annual Meetings, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Annual Meetings, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Chapter Handbook, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
  - Annual Meetings, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Chapter Handbook, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Extension Workers Creed (several copies) (Box 4)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1982-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - ESP Awards of Merit, 1947-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Conference Celebrating 75 Years, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Awards, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - National Conference, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Annual Meeting and Awards, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Recognition Banquet, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Minutes for the Annual Dinner, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Annual Meeting Materials, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Awards Committee, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Annual Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Annual Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Annual Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Annual Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Annual Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Awards, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Awards Banquet, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Recipients of Awards, 1977-1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Budget Summary, 1987-2000 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Meeting Minutes, Agendas, etc., 1983-1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Membership Lists, 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Membership Lists, 1983-1989 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Photographs, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 25)